Frank Muenchmeyer

30 An Mhainistir, Claregalway, Co. Galway Phone: +353 87 168 4152 email: frank.muenchmeyer@gmail.com

Personal Information

Nationality: German

Date of birth: 18th January 1987
Website: http://muenchmeyer.com
Github: https://github.com/rombald

Introduction

Frank Muenchmeyer is a **senior software engineer** with over 8 years experience involving agile software development, analysis, design, implementation and testing of web services. He has a broad experience with server maintenance and cloud computing with Amazon Web Services. Beside of the **development experience**, he was also responsible for **product management** and **software architecture**.

Professional Experience

Since 04/2016 Self-employed Senior Software Engineer

Claregalway, Co. Galway, Ireland

Software development and design, and implementation of new features for several clients

- Backend and frontend development with open source technologies
- Server maintenance of Ubuntu systems based on AWS or root server
- Technologies: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, PHP 5.X, MySQL, HTML, CSS

03/2014 - 03/2016

Senior Software Engineer at **Kumukan GmbH** A company of Deutsche Telekom (T-Mobile) *Product: manualONE (https://www.manualone.com)*

Cologne, Germany

The company developed an App to organize customer products and to find manuals of their products. The user is also able to upload pictures of products and receipts, to add guarantee Informations and generate custom products. The product is available in Web and for iOS and Android devices

- Main responsibility for the architecture of all services based on a microservice infrastructure with Amazon Web Services
- Implementation of new features in the backend services with Ruby on Rails
- Organizing and working in a Scrum based team and establishing of a agile product management
- Setup and maintenance of an self hosted Elasticsearch and a managed Elasticsearch cluster
- Setup the test environment and integration tests with Jenkins
- Loadtesting of all services
- Responsible for the iOS Development with Objective-C
- Main Achievement: Release of the iOS App "manualONE"

03/2009 - 02/2014

Senior Software Engineer at **Adcloud GmbH** A company of Deutsche Post DHL Cologne, Germany

Adcloud was a performance marketing platform which has it's own adserver with realtime bidding functionality and it has it's own revenue based ad delivery. The adserver was tested from Google and certified for Google's ad delivery. Adcloud had also an interface for Website owners and advertisers to manage AdTags and analyse reportings

- Implementation of new services to increase the revenue based ad delivery with Ruby on Rails, CakePHP and MySQL
- Implementing new algorithms into the revenue based ad delivery and further development of the revenue based ad delivery
- Improving the scalability of our internal services and the Node is adserver
- Improving the front- and backend for the customers
- Responsible for the technical corporate liquidation

Software Architect

- Responsible for the architecture of services with Amazon Web Services
- Responsible for the evaluation of new technologies

Product Manager

- Product Manager/Product Owner of one Scrum based team
- Planning new projects, technologies and implementation details

07/2008 - 04/2009

Software Engineer at GIGA Digital Televison GmbH

Cologne, Germany

GIGA was a television channel specialised on videogames. It had a websites with all informations about every show, a news area from a professional editorial staff and also a community driven news area

- Developing landingpages for the customers
- Further development of the company created web-framework
- Developing of community driven games

Side Projects

Since 08/2013

Software Engineer at Cheesy Meat Games (http://cheesy-meat-games.com/en/)

Cheesy Meat Games creates small games for iOS and is a small project to better understand and to learn mobile app development. The games are all available on the iOS AppStore and generated revenue

- Developing a memory based game with Objective-C
- Developing a mathematical game for kids with Objective-C

Education

08/2007 - 07/2008

Vocational school ("Berufsbildende Schulen III"), Magdeburg, Germany Advanced technical college entrance qualification

Specialisation: information technology

08/2005 - 08/2007

Vocational school ("Berufsbildende Schulen III"), Magdeburg, Germany

Degree: Technical assistant for information technology

Technical Skills

Programming languages

- Deep knowledge: Ruby (Ruby on Rails, Sinatra)
- Excellent knowledge: PHP (CakePHP), JavaScript (¡Query, Node.js)
- Basic knowledge: Objective-C, Python (Django)

Development Tools

• Deep knowledge: Git, Subversion

Databases

- Deep knowledge: MySQL
- Excellent knowledge: Redis, CouchDB
- Basic knowledge: Elasticsearch

Monitoring

Excellent knowledge: Icinga, Nagios

Test Tools

- Deep knowledge: RSpec
- Excellent knowledge: PHPUnit
- Basic knowledge: Jenkins, CruiseControl, XCTest

Cloud Technologies

- Deep knowledge: Amazon Web Services
- Basic knowledge: Qbox (https://qbox.io)

Virtualization

- Excellent knowledge: VirtualBox (Vagrant)
- Basic knowledge: Docker, VMware

Additional skills

Languages: German: native speaker

English: business fluent

Driving licence: Full EU